A lot of people reach out saying I want to
take a policy from HDFC Ergo or I want to
port to it.  Have to go with them.   You have to
take HDFC Ergo's Optima Secure or Super Secure.  Why?  Because the
credibility is high.  The complaint ratio
is low.  The incurred claim ratio is very high which is
84.85% as per the latest IRD
Annual Report.  So here a question arises
that the premium of HDFC Ago
is high.  So for high premium of HDFC Ago,
we have made a video in which
we have found a hack on how you can reduce the premium.  You
can buy your desired policy at a low premium without
compromising on any of the benefits.
So it can be a very useful video.  Here
you get a family policy of ₹ lakh for ₹ 10,000.  Let's see how.  But let me tell
you before starting the video.  This is
not a promotional video.  This video is
for those who are specifically looking for HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure policy.  Want to join Optima
Secure or Super Secure or HDFC Ergo because
of high income
claim ratio but get stuck due to premium.
This video is for those who put their decisions on hold.
In the video we will talk to you about how you
can reduce your premium
without compromising on any of the
features.
Quick reminder before starting the video,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so.
So that you get the right
information at the right time.  If you want to consult anything,
you can consult our team
on the given number.  You can consult on this WhatsApp number.
Email ID is given, you
can consult on that.  The Google Form
is embedded in the description box.  You
can fill it and our team will reach out to you at the
earliest.  Let's move on to the video.
HDFC Ago Optima Secure Super Secure at
a lower premium.  ₹10,000 for 30 lax
cover.  Let's see how.  So this is how I have
calculated the premium.  I have
taken a family size here for two adults.  There are two
people, husband and wife.  33 and 30 edges have been taken.  I have
taken premium of Zone 2 and have
taken policy of 10 lakhs.  If
you are taking HDFC Ergo Secure of Rs 10 lakh, Optima
Secure or Super Secure, then you will see
what the premium is, 330 per zone to pay and
10 per zone to pay.  What is the USP of Optima Secure Policy
?  Secure Benefit.  Secure
Benefit is 2X cover from Day One.  So here
your 10 lax becomes 20 lax.
From day one at Optima Secure.  This
is the premium for one year for Optima Secure.
₹18.89 for two people in Zone Two
If two people take a policy who live in Zone Two
and take a policy of Rs 10 lakh
whose cover was Rs 20 lakh from the first day, then the
premium is Rs 18.89.
Now there is a concept called deductible, I would
like to explain that to you.
What is the concept of deductible basically?  So I
took this from the video where I
talked about deductible,
what is deductible actually?
You may also want to refer to the video on Deductible vs Copayment on our channel.
So let us understand the deductible now.  Here
we will ignore age.
I am telling you the deductible concept.  Insurance
deductible is the amount
you have to pay upfront or out of pocket
before the insurance cover kicks in.
Meaning, if you have given ₹25,000 deductible, then in any year when
any claim comes,
you will have to pay ₹25,000 once in a year.  After that, the
insurance
company will pay all the claims that come.  Here the example taken was that
in a policy of Rs 10 lakh, Rs 2 lakh is deductible.
What was the scenario there?  ₹1 lakh
policy ₹1 lakh deductible.  So the first claim
came for ₹ lakh.  How much did you have to pay out of pocket
?  How much did the insurance company pay for ₹2 lakh
?  In the same year, a second claim of
₹8 lakh came.  Now you don't have to pay anything because ₹2
lakh was deductible which you have already paid.
Now the
insurance company will pay the remaining amount of ₹8 lakh.  Similarly,
in Year 2, the first claim came for ₹5 lakh.  Since the
deductible is ₹2 lakh, you have to pay ₹1 lakh.
Whether you pay from corporate cover,
from some other policy or from your own pocket.  On
top of that the insurance company will give ₹3
lakh.  After that again a claim of ₹5 lakh came.   Do
n't pay anything out of pocket.  The insurance
company will provide it.  So, here we can
replace the example with 25,000.  Let's go
back to our HDFC Aego Optima Secure.
And if you want to understand the concept better,
then definitely you can watch this video.   There is
also another video of deductible which
I am putting in the description box
where I have explained the entire deductible to
you on Excel that how the deductible works.
So here you will directly
understand that if there is a deductible of ₹25,000.
Your premium of ₹18.89 has been
reduced by 25%.  So in 1889,
we subtracted 25% and it became ₹1416.
Okay, 25% discount is available
with 25000 deductible. Now
if I take this 50000 deductible of mine, that
if any claim comes in a year, then I have to pay the first ₹00,
after that the insurance company will pay, then
how will you calculate your 40% discount there, you
minus
into 40%,
that becomes ₹1,285,
means you were paying ₹18,000 premium, but
how much cover can you get by paying ₹11,285?  ₹
50,000 deductible with ₹ 50,000 deductible.  So now the best
part is that this Rs 50,000 or Rs 25,000 will
remain the same in the future also.
₹2,000 has some value today.  In the future, you will
see that its value will decrease according to inflation.
So 25,000 is going to remain 25,000.
But the discount percentage is that
you will keep getting a discount of 25% to 40% on your premium every year in the long term.
So a good option is to choose deductible.
When can you choose this?  Firstly,
when you want to get good cover at a lower premium,
you can choose deductible.
Secondly, you have corporate cover.
You say that as long as I work,
I will have corporate insurance.
So why not opt ​​for a deductible
and save on premiums.  So you will
choose a deductible which will reduce your premiums.
The outgo is low.  Suppose the claim does
not come then it is your only benefit.  Meaning,
if you watch the video about deductible,
you will actually feel that this is
my benefit.  It is about my benefit.
So definitely it is a win-win
situation for you as well as for the insurance company.
Here, if I take a 3-year
policy, I am
also getting some multi-tenure discount in 3 years, which
is 10%.  I will also tell you what calculations are coming with it.  If
you pay the premium for 3 years together without
any deductible, it is ₹51,000.  You have
taken ₹25,000 deductible.  The premium became
₹38,530.
Now you say that I have to pay ₹50,000
deductible, then the premium becomes
₹30,824.
So this will be your premium for 3 years.
If you withdraw this per year,
if you are paying Rs 51,000 for 3 years, then it will cost
you Rs 17,000 per year.
With 25, the deductible is ₹1,000.  It costs
₹10,000 with a deductible of ₹50.   This
means you are getting insurance of ₹ lax for ₹ 10,000 per
year.  If you are paying 3
years premium up front.  So this is now
secure.  Now there is a similar super secure option
which is a three year policy Optima Super
Secure.  If you want to know about these plans in detail,
videos are already
available on our channel.  Super Secure One Year and
Two Year plans are not available.  It is only a
three year plan.  So in three years I
put super secure.  Her cover is 3X from Day One.
So the difference between secure and super secure is
that here the cover is from day one to
three times.  So the policy of 10 lax will be
your 30 count from day one.
Now what is the premium here?  Here Rs 51,000 was being given for
secure loan for three years.
Super Secure will cost Rs 5249.  This means
you have to pay a little extra every year.
You were getting almost ₹1000 in 3 years i.e. ₹17124 per year.
Here it is 17483.   That's what
we took the deductible.
3 years costing Rs 39,000 with Rs 25,000 and Rs 31,000 with Rs
50 deductible.  So, if you calculate ₹1,000 per year in 3 years
Super Secure, it is
₹1,000 and ₹10,000 with a
deductible of 50.  So for ₹1,000 you are getting 30 lacs
cover from day one.  I think this
is great and
you are getting the insurance company of your choice.  If we
look at the cover, it is a good cover to a great extent.
Meaning the cover is not less than 30 lakhs.  So
from the cover point of view as well as from the premium point of
view.  I think it's a good
proposal.  Choosing a deductible is a wise
decision.  And the biggest thing is that this annual
aggregate is deductible.  It will not be applicable on every claim.
This will be applicable only on the first claim in a year.
If you are exploring
HDFC Ergo policy, then do
not forget to apply this hack.  Get the policy from anywhere.
Get it from your local agent.
Get it directly from HDFCO.  If you want to get it through us then
our contact number and email ID
are mentioned.  You can reach out to us.
Take it from anywhere but don't forget to apply the deductible hack.
Because the premium will remain low even in the long term.
Its control will be
your premium and then deductible option.  If you
want to understand the deductible in more detail, there are
links to the videos below.  Please do refer that
before taking any decision.  And don't forget to do your due
diligence.
Choose the deductible option only after understanding the concept completely.
Because once you choose it, you will be
able to exit it only after 5 years.  There
is an easy switch option.  Can exit after 5 years.  There are
terms and conditions in that too.  One can
exit only after underwriting is done.
So you should keep this in mind that if you have taken
deductible then you have taken it for life.  There
is an option to exit but whether it is possible or
not will depend on the underwriting and there are
some terms and conditions also.  So that's all
I wanted to tell you.  And if you have any
queries, you can reach out to us.
As I told you, our WhatsApp
number and calling number is 965070699, you
can mail us or fill the Google form on info hp.com,
our team will connect with
you at the earliest. And before leaving, a quick
reminder, don't forget to share this video with your friends
and don't forget to subscribe to our channel
so that
we can keep sharing such useful information with you.
See you soon with a new video.  Till then
stay safe.  Take care.  Bye-bye.
Om